BROOKE KUMAR, PMP

Austin, TX | (651) 399-3097 | mrsbrookekumar@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/brooke-kumar/

PROGRAM & PORTFOLIO MANAGER

Experienced program manager with a collaborative approach excelling in building high-performing teams, identifying potential issues, and developing effective strategies to mitigate risks. An ability to manage competing priorities and adapt to changing environments has been key to much success and passion about driving innovation and delivering tangible business outcomes. Thrilled to bring skills and experience to a new challenge as a program manager.

SKILLS

Program Management | Contract procurement/execution | Process Improvement |
Change Management | Vendor Management | Stakeholder Management | Visio | MS Project | Power
Pivot | Power Query | Advanced VLOOKUP | SharePoint Admin and Creation | GitHub | Spotfire | JIRA |
Zendesk | Confluence | Excel | PowerPoint | Tableau | Internal Meta tools

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Meta, Austin, TX

June 2022-July 2023 (Laid off)

Quality Operation Program Manager

As a part of Global Operations, I was responsible for scaling Quality business processes and monitoring Quality performance for third-party business vendors. As a senior member of my team, I led several global programs from a Quality perspective resulting in simplified processes engaging critical stakeholders using existing internal systems. I ramped up into my role very quickly, taking on complex programs across content learning, feedback cycles, and metrics improvements in under 2 months.

- Acted as the key Quality Operations stakeholder in OpEx savings exercises leading to \$80M+ realized savings for the Policy and Trust organization.
- Established scalable Program Management best-practices within Quality Operations improving cross-functional collaboration and productivity churn for internal and external stakeholders.

Medtronic, Los Angeles, CA, Remote **Senior Business Systems Analyst**

July 2021-June 2022

Managed global resources for execution of customer-facing software projects. Navigated a matrix organization with varying stakeholders across Corporate, User Experience, Engineering, IT, Marketing, Legal, and Sales. Mentored other employees on software processes and document activities for content and learning purposes.

- Iterated on existing features and built out the remaining B2C and B2B core product requirements while leading 40+ third-party vendor contractor technical resources.
- Created and led risk mitigation strategy for shared services platform implementation (\$10M infrastructure spend)

L7 Informatics, Austin, TX, Remote

February 2021-July 2021

Integration Program Manager

Delivered exceptional performance in transforming customer needs into system requirements and planned / executed multiple programs from design to production simultaneously. Managed on-boarding of new employees by screening, interviewing, and selecting best-fit candidates to join growing PMO. Utilized formal documentation practices with use of hybrid methodology (Agile and Waterfall), while drafting vivid and complete requirements of moderate scope and complexity solutions to lead and streamline software development operations.

- Improved core product performance and internal PMO SOPs by overseeing documentations of processes, system, and application use cases.
- Resolved business/product issues, including bug fixes, improvements, and maintenance by leading cross-functional linked teams.
- Implemented project management practices in accordance with top standards from planning to maintenance by using Jira and templates.
- Improved communication and response time by increasing internal stakeholders' transparency by 25%

Cloudflare, Austin, TX, Remote Portfolio Manager, Transit and IXP

2020-2021

Increased network connectivity across 250 cities world-wide, while liaising with clients for service procurement of \$30M between two rising product verticals (Transit and IXP)

- Mentored and steered internal colleagues work to infrastructure and in other workstreams.
- Utilized effective strategies to accomplish 6 months of delayed tasks in under 3 months resulting in \$10M backlogged procurement spend.
- Designed and implemented a budget tracking and approval system to ensure adequate funding to each department for effective functioning.
- Ensured efficient procuring services by enhancing and planning effective business procedures.

Medtronic, Mounds View, MN

2017-2020

PD Project Management Specialist (CRHF RPE-EU MDR)

Collaborated with Program Director / Program Managers in managing initiatives across Quality, Labeling, Regulatory, Clinical, Materials Engineering and Operations.

- Analyzed products for remediation specific to the CRHF/AFS business unit by managing a comprehensive product portfolio.
- Enhanced program planning of +\$100M internal program through utilizing and improving existing Medtronic tools and applications.
- Achieved top-performer title from manager at annual review (limited to top 5% of the entire organization)
- Ensured project management practices in accordance with standards/frameworks for a \$+100M program from inception to completion.

ADDITIONAL RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Consulting for Abbott Laboratories, St. Paul, MN **EU MDR Business Analyst, Experis**

DaVita Clinical Research, Minneapolis, MN **Regulatory Affairs Associate**

EDUCATION, AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

Bachelor Of Arts in Religious Studies
Minor In Sociology
Carthage College

Project Management Professional (PMP) Credential ID: 2763949 (Active since May 2020)

Certificate, Full-Stack Web DevelopmentUniversity of Minnesota (Trilogy Boot Camp) (2020)

Bachelor of Arts in Religious Studies
Minor in Sociology
Carthage College

Best Thesis, Humanities Department

Carthage College (2014)

Best Thesis, Religious Studies Department
Carthage College (2014)